6323 Martel Court, Mississauga, ON L5N 3H6 | (647) 801 – 0946 | sirajrauff@gmail.com

#### PROJECTS Project Manager – Engineering Capstone Project

Sep 2015 - Present

Acting Project Manager for the Engineering Capstone Project degree requirement at York University. Made use of Unity Game Editor to design *Botanica*, a virtual-reality application simulating a gardening experience on a PC, Mac, or Android phone. Efficiently split, prioritized and delegated tasks in a small group utilizing collaborative software including Github and Office 365. Applied the Agile Development methodology with weekly SCRUM meetings to ensure timely deliverables without sacrificing quality of content.

#### Migration of Staff Applications To Web (C++ and Visual Prolog)

Mar 2015 - Present

Recreated C++/Visual Prolog programs as web applications using jQuery, HTML and CSS to allow end-users to connect without the use of virtualization software. Made heavy use of AJAX, JSON and JavaScript Promises within a custom framework based on WebObjects to allow for responsive design. Utilized Atlassian Confluence and Fisheye for collaborative development and documentation. Communicated with other departments throughout the development process to ensure programs met the clients' needs.

#### **OEN (Ontario Education Number) Web Service**

Jan 2015 - Feb 2015

Collaborated with the Ontario Ministry of Education to develop an application to verify government student data against university records in Java using JDBC + prepared SQL statements and the Apache Axis2 engine to provide SOAP functionality. Validated over 95% of students automatically through different combinational attempts, saving months of work hours relative to previous manual validation methods.

#### **Grade Point Average Calculator**

Nov 2014 – Feb 2015

Modified an existing SQL procedure that automatically calculated normalized York GPAs for incoming transfer students from other institutions to deal with institutions that did not comply with agreed formatting standards for electronic document transfers. Project resulted in sub-second response time and automatic handling of 99.5% of applicants in 25/26 institutions.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Full Stack Web Developer/Java and SQL Programmer

Aug 2014 – Present

Student Information Systems (SIS), York University

- Work as part of a team developing Java/C++ programs and jQuery Web Applications in a UNIX environment.
- Utilize CVS/SVN + Atlassian Fisheye for versioning and collaboration, Atlassian Confluence for Documentation, and BMC Remedy for ticket management.
- Use SQL to create/modify procedures, functions, tables and reports in order to provide clients with requested information as well as automatically sort and process information received by the University.

#### **Helpdesk Assistant**

Aug 2013 - Aug 2014

University Information Technology (UIT), York University

- Provided front-line support for computer, network and account management to students and faculty through email, phone, online chat or in person.
- Supervised computer labs, maintaining and troubleshooting lab equipment.
- Used problem solving skills and critical thinking to diagnose and fix email, software and virtualization issues with clients' computers on a variety of operating systems.

## Siraj Rauff

6323 Martel Court, Mississauga, ON L5N 3H6 | (647) 801 – 0946 | sirajrauff@gmail.com

#### EDUCATION

#### B.Eng., Spec. Hons. Software Engineering

York University, Toronto

Expected April 2017

- Project Manager for Engineering Capstone Project Fall 2015 Winter 2016 creating a Virtual Reality Garden aimed at low mobility individuals.
- Top of class in Design Patterns and System Specification and Refinement
- Collaborated with a team using software including Github and BugZilla to develop a Java program to translate ASCII guitar tablatures to PDF music sheets.
- Software Engineering Representative on the York Engineering Society for Fall 2013
- Winner of the 2012 Murphy's Cup: worked as part of a team to design and build a robot to autonomously navigate an obstacle course in the shortest period of time.

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Documentation/Project
Management Tools

Languages/Notations

Microsoft Office Suite, Atlassian Fisheye/Confluence, Slack, Google Docs, Basecamp, Texworks and Remedy IT Suite

C/C++, Java, CSS/HTML/XML, JavaScript/jQuery, JSON/AJAX, Event-B, LaTeX, MIPS, Bash/Python, SQL (Oracle 9i,11g; DB2),

Verilog, WebObjects/Wonder Framework

Operating Systems Linux, Windows, OS X, iOS, Android

Development Tools

Android Studio, Eclipse, EiffelStudio, SQL Developer, Visual

Studio

**Version Control** 

**Systems** 

Github, CVS, SVN

Programs Citrix Receiver, Oracle VirtualBox, PTC Creo, Moneris POS